medicinescomplete.com 2014-07-20

# Cookie and Privacy Policy: MedicinesComplete

This Website www.medicinescomplete.com (`Website`) is operated by Pharmaceutical Press, the publications division of the **Royal Pharmaceutical Society of Great Britain** (Company Number RC000799) whose registered office is 1 Lambeth High Street, London, SE1 7JN, England (`PhP`). 

This Cookie and Privacy Policy covers this Website [www.medicinescomplete.com](http://www.medicinescomplete.com/) (the " **Website** "). PhP respects the privacy of every individual who visits this Website. This Policy sets out how PhP may use or disclose personal information about visitors to this Website and their rights in relation to that information. By entering and using this Website you are deemed to accept all terms and conditions outlined in this Policy. 

## 1\. Collection of Personal Information from Website Visitors

PhP may collect and/or track:

  1. the home server domain names, e-mail addresses, operating system, and type of Web browser of visitors to this Website;
  2. the e-mail addresses of visitors who communicate with PhP via e-mail;
  3. information provided by the visitor in online forms, registration forms surveys, and contest entries (including demographic, financial and personal profile data);
  4. aggregate and user-specific information on which pages visitors access; and
  5. payment information and financial details about our customers.

**Use of Cookies**

This website uses cookies to collect information about what areas of the site users visit and to enable the website's login functionality. A cookie is a piece of information saved in a text file that is placed on your computer's hard drive.

The following cookies are enabled on our website.

Type: Google Analytics

Name: _utma _utmb _utmc _utmz

Reason for use: We collect anonymous information about all website visitors, such as the number of times a page is visited and searches performed using the search function. This information is used in order to understand how the website is being used and this helps us improve your user experience. For more information please visit [www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html). 

Type: Session Cookie

Name: as _rf _session_id wccjsessionid

Reason for use: These cookies are used to remember what you have put in your shopping basket and to operate the payment function. Without these cookies the purchasing process will not function correctly. The MedicinesComplete Feedback function also uses session cookies if you choose to provide feedback using this method.

Type: Persistent Cookie

Name: d0 sdo _uservoice_tz _uservoice_utcd _csuid

Reason for use: These cookies help govern access to the site and are needed for the login process, subscription information and the timeout function. Without these cookies you will not be able to access the site and will be redirected to a page requiring you to turn cookies on. The MedicinesComplete Feedback function also uses persistent cookies if you choose to provide feedback using this method.

You may decline or disable cookies when using the website. However if you disable certain persistent cookies (such as d0) you will not be able to access the site and will be redirected to a page requiring you turn cookies on. By disabling other cookies the site will not recognise you when you return and the payment, feedback and shopping basket functions will not work. As the means by which you can refuse cookies varies from browser to browser, please consult your web browser's help menu for further information on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Further information on deleting or controlling cookies is available at [www.AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). 

## 2\. Use of Personal Data Collected

Personal data collected by PhP may be used by PhP for editorial feedback purposes, for marketing and promotional purposes, for statistical analysis of visitors' behaviour, for product development, for content improvement, to customise the content and layout of this Website, to solve technical problems with this Website service, or to calculate overall usage statistics.

Information collected by Google is primarily used to optimise this Website for our visitors and to monitor the service that the Website provides. You cannot be individually identified from this data. The aggregate data may be shared with third parties (see section 3).

Financial information is used for billing purposes and to fulfil customers' orders. Financial information is held on our secure server with restricted access (see section 5 on Security measures).

Aggregate data (which does not identify individuals) on home server domain names, operating system, referral URL and type of web browser may be used for internal purposes. Your name, IP address and login details (email address and password) are used to gain access to the Website.

Individually identifying information, such as names, postal and e-mail addresses, phone numbers, and other personal information, which visitors voluntarily provide to PhP, may be added to the PhP databases and used for future calls and mailings regarding Website updates, new products and services, upcoming events and the status of orders placed online. See section 6 for details on opting out.

The personal data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). Please be aware that such countries may not offer the same level of data protection as countries within the EEA. Your personal data may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our affiliated organisations. By submitting your personal data, you agree to the transfer, storing and processing of your data in this way. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely, in accordance with this privacy policy and in accordance with European Standards.

## 3\. Disclosure of Personal Data to Third Parties

Unless it is required to do so by law, PhP does not sell, license, share or intentionally make publicly available any individually identifying information to third parties other than its agents or contractors, such as its software developers, distributors or professional advisers, for the purposes of operating this Website and developing, manufacturing and distributing PhP products.

Google collect and aggregate non-personally identifiable information on Your visit to the Website. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process information on Google's behalf. No personal information that could be used by Google to identify You is transmitted to Google. Google also undertake not to associate Your IP address with any other data held by them, for example personal information You may have submitted to the in the course of Your personal use of other Google services (i.e. Google Mail).

## 4\. External Links

This Website may contain links to other sites. PhP is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites unless they are owned and operated by PhP. We encourage our visitors to be aware when they leave this Website and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected through or in connection with this Website.

## 5\. Security Measures

PhP has implemented security features to prevent the unauthorised release of or access to visitors' personal information. In particular, when a visitor places an order for Publications available on this Website via email, a secure server is used to store all order and payment information securely. Please be advised, however, that while PhP has endeavoured to create a completely secure Website, the Internet is not a 100% secure medium for the communication of information and PhP is not responsible for the security of information transmitted via the Internet. Accordingly, the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to or from PhP via Website or e-mail cannot be guaranteed.

All of our visitors' personal information, not just the financial information described above, is made available only to those employees or contractors who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our finance department and sales or customer service representatives, distributors or software developers).

## 6\. Opt-Out Right

You may opt out of having Your personal information used by PhP for marketing and promotional purposes, by contacting either the sales or customer services departments of PhP via post, e-mail or telephone at the addresses posted at the links in section 10, or by unchecking the appropriate box while accessing Your account through this Website.

## 7\. Access to and Ability to Correct Personal Data

Upon request via post or e-mail PhP will provide to visitors any personal information stored by PhP regarding the visitor.(Pharmaceutical Press reserves the right to charge a reasonable fee for fulfilling such requests). Visitors may correct or update their personal record or cause their personal record to be removed from the Pharmaceutical Press database. Please note that Pharmaceutical Press will only send personal records to the e-mail address on file for the visitor name associated with it.

## 8\. Our Right to Contact the Visitor

PhP reserves the right to contact Website visitors regarding their account status and changes to the subscriber agreement, this Privacy Policy, or any other policies or agreements relevant to Website visitors.

## 9\. Our Right to Change this Privacy Policy

This Policy is effective as of 30 May 2012. PhP reserves the right to change this Policy at any time by publishing on this Website notice of the existence and location of the new or revised Policy. Visitors should periodically review this Policy to make sure it meets their needs.

## 10\. How to Contact Us

See the Contact Us page for details of how to contact us.
